In the past few months, I've been traveling for weeks at a time
خلال الأشهر الماضية، كنت أسافر لعدة أسابيع متتالية كل مرة
with only one suitcase of clothes.
مصطحبةً حقيبة ملابس واحدة.
One day, I was invited to an important event,
وفي أحد الأيام دعيت إلى حدث مهم،
and I wanted to wear something special and new for it.
وأردت أن أرتدي ملابس جديدة خاصة بالمناسبة.
So I looked through my suitcase and I couldn't find anything to wear.
وبعد أن بحثت في حقيبتي لم أجد شيئًا مناسبًا لألبسه.
I was lucky to be at the technology conference on that day,
ومن حسن حظي أني كنت في مؤتمر التكنولوجيا ذلك اليوم،
and I had access to 3D printers.
مع إمكانية استخدامي لطابعة ثلاثية الأبعاد.
So I quickly designed a skirt on my computer,
فقمت على عجل بتصميم تنورة على حاسبي،
and I loaded the file on the printer.
وحملت الملف على الطابعة.
It just printed the pieces overnight.
وتمت طباعتها كقطعٍ خلال الليل.
The next morning, I just took all the pieces,
في الصباح التالي، أخذت كل القطع،
assembled them together in my hotel room,
وجمعتها في غرفتي في الفندق،
and this is actually the skirt that I'm wearing right now.
و في الحقيقة هذه هي التنورة التي ألبسها الآن.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So it wasn't the first time that I printed clothes.
لم تكن تلك المرة الأولى التي طبعت فيها ملابس.
For my senior collection at fashion design school,
من أجل مشروع تخرجي من مدرسة تصميم الأزياء،
I decided to try and 3D print an entire fashion collection from my home.
قررت طباعة مجموعة أزياء كاملة من منزلي.
The problem was that I barely knew anything about 3D printing,
ولكن المشكلة كانت معرفتي الضئيلة بالطباعة ثلاثية الأبعاد،
and I had only nine months to figure out how to print five fashionable looks.
وكل ما كان لدي هو 9 أشهر لتعلم كيفية طباعة 5 قطع عصرية.
I always felt most creative when I worked from home.
دائمًا كنت أشعر أن إبداعي يزداد عندما أعمل من منزلي.
I loved experimenting with new materials,
أحببت تجريب مواد جديدة،
and I always tried to develop new techniques
وطالما حاولت تطوير تقنياتٍ جديدة
to make the most unique textiles for my fashion projects.
للوصول إلى منسوجات فريدة من أجل مشاريع الأزياء الخاصة بي.
I loved going to old factories and weird stores
أحببت زيارة المصانع القديمة والمحال الغريبة
in search of leftovers of strange powders and weird materials,
للبحث عن بقايا مساحيق غير مألوفة ومواد عجيبة،
and then bring them home to experiment on.
لتجريبها في المنزل.
As you can probably imagine,
كما يمكنكم تصور
my roommates didn't like that at all.
أن زملائي بالسكن لم يعحبهم ذلك أبدًا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So I decided to move on to working with big machines,
لذا قررت الانتقال للعمل على آلاتٍ أكبر،
ones that didn't fit in my living room.
كبيرة بحيث لا تتسع لها عرفة المعيشة.
I love the exact and the custom work I can do
أحب العمل التقليدي والدقيق الذي كنت أقوم به
with all kinds of fashion technologies,
باستخدام كل تكنولوجيا الأزياء،
like knitting machines and laser cutting and silk printing.
كآلات الحياكة والقص بالليزر والطباعة على الحرير.
One summer break, I came here to New York for an internship
في إحدى عطل الصيف، جئت إلى هنا إلى نيويورك كمتدربة
at a fashion house in Chinatown.
في بيت للأزياء في الحي الصيني.
We worked on two incredible dresses that were 3D printed.
عملنا على فستانين رائعين تم طبعهم بطابعة ثلاثية الأبعاد.
They were amazing -- like you can see here.
كانا رائعين كما ترون.
But I had a few issues with them.
ولكن كانت لدي بعض المشاكل معهم.
They were made from hard plastics and that's why they were very breakable.
صنعا من بلاستيك قاسي مما عرضهما للكسر.
The models couldn't sit in them,
لم يكن بمقدور العارضات الجلوس،
and they even got scratched from the plastics under their arms.
كما تسببا بخدوش تحت الساعدين.
With 3D printing, the designers had so much freedom
الطباعة ثلاثية الأبعاد توفر حرية كبيرة للمصممين
to make the dresses look exactly like they wanted,
لجعل الفساتين تبدو بالشكل الذي يرغبونه،
but still, they were very dependent on big and expensive industrial printers
ولكن، كان اعتمادهم على طابعات كبيرة صناعية مكلفة
that were located in a lab far from their studio.
موجودة في مختبر بعيد عن مكان عملهم.
Later that year, a friend gave me a 3D printed necklace,
لاحقًا تلك السنة، أعطاني صديق عقدًا مطبوعًا بشكلٍ ثلاثي الأبعاد
printed using a home printer.
مطبوعًا بطابعة منزلية.
I knew that these printers were much cheaper
علمت بعدها أن هذه الطابعات كانت أرخص بكثير
and much more accessible than the ones we used at my internship.
ومتوفرة أكثر من التي كنا نستخدمها خلال فترة تدريبي.
So I looked at the necklace,
لذا نظرت إلى العقد،
and then I thought, "If I can print a necklace from home,
وفكرت أنه إذا كان بإمكاني طباعة عقد في منزلي،
why not print my clothes from home, too?"
لماذا لا أطبع ملابسي في المنزل أيضًا؟
I really liked the idea that I wouldn't have to go to the market
أعجبتني فكرة عدم اضطراري للذهاب إلى السوق
and pick fabrics that someone else chose to sell --
واختيار القماش المعروض للبيع من شخصٍ غريب.
I could just design them and print them directly from home.
بإمكاني تصميم القماش وطباعته مباشرة من منزلي.
I found a small makerspace,
وجدت ورشةً صغيرةً،
where I learned everything I know about 3D printing.
تعلمت فيها كل ما أعرفه عن الطباعة ثلاثية الأبعاد.
Right away, they literally gave me the key to the lab,
مباشرةً أعطوني مفتاح المخبر،
so I could experiment into the night, every night.
لأتمكن من التجريب طوال الليل، كل ليلة.
The main challenge was to find the right filament for printing clothes with.
التحدي الرئيسي كان إيجاد الخيط المناسب لطباعة الملابس.
So what is a filament?
ماهو الخيط؟
Filament is the material you feed the printer with.
الخيط هو المادة التي تضعها في الطابعة.
And I spent a month or so experimenting with PLA,
وأمضيت قرابة الشهر أختبر مادة بي.إل.إيه.
which is a hard and scratchy, breakable material.
وهي مادة قاسية وخشنة وقابلة للكسر.
The breakthrough came when I was introduced to Filaflex,
الانفراج جاء عندما عرضت علي مادة "فيلفلاكس"
which is a new kind of filament.
وهي نوع جديد من الخيوط.
It's strong, yet very flexible.
تمتاز بصلابتها ومرونتها.
And with it, I was able to print the first garment,
وباستخدامها تمكنت من طباعة أولى القطع،
the red jacket that had the word "Liberté" --
السترة الحمراء التي تحمل كلمة "حرية" --
"freedom" in French --
بالفرنسية..
embedded into it.
كجزء منها.
I chose this word because I felt so empowered and free
اخترت هذه الكلمة لشعوري بالسلطة والحرية
when I could just design a garment from my home
حيث بإمكاني تصميم قطعة ملابس من منزلي
and then print it by myself.
وطباعتها بنفسي.
And actually, you can easily download this jacket,
في الواقع، يمكنك تنزيل هذه السترة بسهولة،
and easily change the word to something else.
وتغيير الكلمة بسهولة.
For example, your name or your sweetheart's name.
على سبيل المثال، اسمك أو اسم حبيبك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So the printer plates are small,
و كما كانت لوحات الطابعة صغيرة،
so I had to piece the garment together, just like a puzzle.
تحتم علي تركيب قطعة الملابس، كلعبة التركيب.
And I wanted to solve another challenge.
أردت حل مشكلة أخرى.
I wanted to print textiles
أردت طباعة منسوجات
that I would use just like regular fabrics.
لاستخدامها كالأقمشة العادية.
That's when I found an open-source file
وعندها وجدت ملفًا مفتوح المصدر
from an architect who designed a pattern that I love.
كتبه مهندس معماري صمم نمطًا أحببته.
And with it, I was able to print a beautiful textile
وباستخدامه، تمكنت من طباعة نسيجٍ جميل
that I would use just like a regular fabric.
يمكنني استخدامه كالقماش العادي.
And it actually even looks a little bit like lace.
في الواقع يشبه الشريط قليلًا.
So I took his file and I modified it, and changed it, played with it --
فأخذت ملفه وعدلته، و غيرته، ولعبت به --
many kinds of versions out of it.
وتوصلت إلى نسخٍ عديدة منه.
And I needed to print another 1,500 more hours
واحتجت إلى 1500 ساعة أخرى من الطباعة
to complete printing my collection.
للانتهاء من طباعة مجموعتي.
So I brought six printers to my home and just printed 24-7.
لذا جلبت 6 طابعات إلى منزلي للعمل دون انقطاع.
And this is actually a really slow process,
و في الحقيقة جرى العمل ببطىء شديد،
but let's remember the Internet was significantly slower 20 years ago,
ولكن لنتذكر أن الانترنت كان بطيئًا جدًا منذ 20 عامًا،
so 3D printing will also accelerate
فسيتم تسريع الطباعة ثلاثية الأبعاد أيضًا
and in no time you'll be able to print a T-Shirt in your home
وخلال وقت قصير ستتمكن من طباعة كنزتك في منزلك
in just a couple of hours, or even minutes.
خلال ساعتين أو حتى خلال دقائق.
So you guys, you want to see what it looks like?
هل تريدون رؤية كيف تبدو؟
Audience: Yeah!
الحضور:"أجل!"
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Danit Peleg: Rebecca is wearing one of my five outfits.
دانيت بالغ:"ريبيكا تلبس أحد القطع الخمسة."
Almost everything here she's wearing, I printed from my home.
تقريبًا كل ما تلبسه تمت طباعته في منزلي.
Even her shoes are printed.
حتى حذائها مطبوع.
Audience: Wow!
الحضور: "ياللدهشة"
Audience: Cool!
الحضور: "رائع"
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Danit Peleg: Thank you, Rebecca.
دانيت بالغ:"شكرًا لك، ريبيكا"
(To audience) Thank you, guys.
(للحضور) شكرًا لكم.
So I think in the future, materials will evolve,
أعتقد أنه في المستقبل ستتطور المواد،
and they will look and feel like fabrics we know today,
وستبدو وتولد إحساس الأقمشة الحالية،
like cotton or silk.
كالقطن والحرير.
Imagine personalized clothes that fit exactly to your measurements.
تخيلوا ملابس بلمسة شخصية بمقاسٍ مثالي.
Music was once a very physical thing.
الموسيقى كانت مادية في البداية.
You would have to go to the record shop and buy CDs,
كان يجب عليك الذهاب للمتجر وشراء الأسطوانات المدمجة،
but now you can just download the music --
ولكن الآن يمكنك تنزيل الموسيقى --
digital music --
موسيقى رقمية --
directly to your phone.
مباشرةً إلى هاتفك.
Fashion is also a very physical thing.
الأزياء أيضًا مادية.
And I wonder what our world will look like
وأتسائل كيف سيبدو عالمنا
when our clothes will be digital, just like this skirt is.
عندما ستصبح ملابسنا رقمية، كهذه التنورة.
Thank you so much.
شكرًا جزيلا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
[Thank You]
شكرًا